<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Benjamin Patch</title><link href="https://www.benjaminpatch.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.benjaminpatch.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.benjaminpatch.com/</id><updated>2024-12-18T12:24:00-08:00</updated><subtitle>Guides for Building Ethical &amp; Impactful AI Software</subtitle><entry><title>The Journey of Artificial Intelligence</title><link href="https://www.benjaminpatch.com/posts/2024/Dec/18/journey-of-artificial-intelligence/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-18T12:24:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T12:24:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Benjamin Patch</name></author><id>tag:www.benjaminpatch.com,2024-12-18:/posts/2024/Dec/18/journey-of-artificial-intelligence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AI has become a cornerstone of modern technology, impacting virtually every industry in today's economy. But how did we get here? Let’s explore its fascinating history, from the coining of the term to the rise of machine learning, artificial neural networks, and generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) has become a cornerstone of modern technology, impacting virtually every industry in today's economy. But how did we get here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey of AI spans decades of experimentation, breakthroughs, and debates. Let’s explore its fascinating history, from the coining of the term to the rise of machine learning, artificial neural networks, and generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Defining Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, AI refers to systems that exhibit behavior that we would typically associate with human intelligence. However, defining human intelligence itself is a complex task. Intelligence manifests itself in a wide variety of forms such as artistic expression, mathematical prowess, and problem-solving skills just to name a few. Plus, there's no universal standard for measurement – making it difficult to definitively label a computer as "intelligent."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While computers excel at specific tasks like playing chess or recognizing patterns, they lack the general understanding and awareness that humans possess. They might be able to follow rules and algorithms flawlessly, but it’s important to understand that even the most advanced AI systems at this time, do not grasp the purpose behind their actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Artificial Intelligence is Born&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1955, the legendary computer scientist John McCarthy coined the term "artificial intelligence" to secure funding for the very first AI workshop. This event, held in 1956, aimed to explore whether computers could exhibit behaviors humans would consider intelligent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the limited computational power of the era, this workshop launched the field well beyond academics. The term “artificial intelligence” captured imaginations and inspired generations of scientists, writers, and technologists. Without McCarthy’s vision and knack for branding, it’s possible AI might have languished as an academic curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Early AI: Rules and Symbols&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early AI research was dominated by &lt;strong&gt;symbolic reasoning&lt;/strong&gt;. Scientists like Allen Newell and Herbert Simon developed the "General Problem Solver," a program designed to solve problems expressed mathematically. Their work was rooted in the "Physical Symbol System Hypothesis," asserting that intelligence could emerge from linking symbolic representations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to “expert systems” that could perform tasks like medical diagnosis or financial analysis by following pre-defined steps. However, they were limited by the sheer number of rules required to handle complex scenarios. A problem that became known as “combinatorial explosion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From Symbols to Machine Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the late 1980s, researchers realized symbolic reasoning had limits, especially in environments requiring adaptability. Enter &lt;strong&gt;machine learning (ML)&lt;/strong&gt;, a paradigm shift that allowed computers to learn patterns from data rather than relying on predefined rules. This marked a turning point, where machines transitioned from rigid problem-solving to flexible learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest successes in ML came in 1959 when Arthur Samuel developed a checkers-playing program that improved by playing against itself. This demonstrated that machines could "teach" themselves strategies, opening doors to more advanced applications. Samuel’s program was a landmark, showing that AI could evolve beyond predefined knowledge to adapt and improve autonomously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Neural Networks and Deep Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 1980s, Geoff Hinton and others revitalized interest in &lt;strong&gt;artificial neural networks&lt;/strong&gt;, an approach inspired by the human brain. These networks, organized in layers, excelled at identifying patterns in data. By the 1990s, advancements in &lt;strong&gt;deep learning&lt;/strong&gt; introduced architectures with even more layers, enabling AI to tackle more complex tasks, from image recognition to natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning’s power lies in its ability to process massive datasets, identifying patterns beyond human perception. For instance, Google’s DeepMind famously defeated the world champion of Go, a game far more complex than chess, by leveraging deep learning to analyze millions of potential moves. This victory highlighted how AI could master tasks previously thought too intricate for machines, reshaping industries like gaming, healthcare, and logistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning also benefited from advancements in hardware, particularly GPUs, which greatly accelerated computation. Coupled with the explosion of available data on the internet, neural networks have become a dominant force in AI research and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Big Data Fuels AI’s Growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid progress of AI over the last two decades owes much to the explosion of Big Data and the rise of data science. Massive datasets, generated from social media, sensors, e-commerce, and more, provide the raw material needed for AI systems to learn and improve. These datasets allow machine learning models to uncover patterns and make predictions with unprecedented accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, managing Big Data poses its own challenges. Collecting, storing, and processing such enormous datasets require robust infrastructure and advanced tools. Organizations increasingly use cloud platforms and distributed computing frameworks to handle the scale and complexity of Big Data effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Role of Data Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science bridges the gap between raw data and actionable insights. Combining statistics, computer science, and domain expertise, data scientists analyze and preprocess data to make it usable for AI applications. They clean datasets, identify trends, and engineer features that enhance the performance of machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science also plays a crucial role in interpreting the results of AI models. For example, while an AI system might identify a correlation between specific behaviors and purchasing decisions, it’s often up to data scientists to contextualize these findings and derive meaningful business strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, Big Data and data science have &lt;strong&gt;enabled AI to move from theoretical possibilities to practical applications&lt;/strong&gt; that impact daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Generative AI: Machines That Create&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While traditional AI focuses on analyzing data, generative AI takes it a step further by creating new content. Systems like &lt;strong&gt;large language models (LLMs)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;generative adversarial networks (GANs)&lt;/strong&gt; can produce text, code, images, music, and even video. These advancements hinge on foundational models – massive networks trained on diverse datasets – and techniques like self-supervised learning, which labels data autonomously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generative AI represents a significant leap forward, blurring the lines between human creativity and machine capability. Applications like OpenAI’s GPT and DALL•E have demonstrated AI’s ability to write stories, generate artwork, and even assist in scientific discovery. However, it also raises &lt;a href="/posts/2024/Dec/11/responsible-ai-ethical-principles-for-humanity/"&gt;ethical questions&lt;/a&gt; about authenticity, bias, and the role of humans in creative industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technology’s potential is immense but must be approached cautiously. For instance, deepfake technology, a byproduct of generative AI, has sparked concerns about misinformation and privacy. Policymakers, technologists, and ethicists are now grappling with how to ensure these tools are used responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lessons from AI’s History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evolution of AI underscores the importance of adapting to new challenges and opportunities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Days:&lt;/strong&gt; Symbolic reasoning laid the groundwork but struggled with real-world complexity. These early systems were limited to structured environments like games and predefined problem sets.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Enabled AI to learn from data, bypassing the rigidity of rule-based systems. This adaptability marked a significant shift, allowing AI to tackle broader applications.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Leveraged massive datasets to tackle tasks once thought impossible for machines. Advances in hardware and data accessibility have supercharged this field, enabling breakthroughs in fields ranging from medicine to entertainment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As AI continues to evolve, its history offers a valuable perspective on innovation. By appreciating the breakthroughs and setbacks of the past, we can better navigate the ethical and practical challenges of tomorrow. Whether it’s a chess game or a generative AI model writing poetry, the story of AI is, at its core, a reflection of humanity’s drive to understand and innovate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, this journey reminds us that AI’s success has always depended on human vision and creativity. As we look ahead, it’s not just about building smarter machines but about ensuring they serve humanity’s best interests, fostering collaboration, and unlocking new frontiers of possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional References and Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence"&gt;Wikipedia article on artificial intelligence&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/artificial-intelligence/"&gt;Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy article on intelligence&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dartmouth_Summer_Research_Project_on_Artificial_Intelligence"&gt;Dartmouth Summer Research Project on Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_McCarthy_(computer_scientist)"&gt;John McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Problem_Solver"&gt;General Problem Solver&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ai.stanford.edu/~nilsson/OnlinePubs-Nils/PublishedPapers/pssh.pdf"&gt;Physical Symbol System Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expert_system"&gt;Expert systems&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arthur_Samuel_(computer_scientist)"&gt;Arthur Samuel&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network"&gt;Artificial neural network&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning"&gt;Deep learning&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geoffrey_Hinton"&gt;Geoffrey Hinton&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_adversarial_network"&gt;Generative Adversarial Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="AI Fundamentals"></category><category term="symbolic reasoning"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="neural networks"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="generative ai"></category></entry><entry><title>Responsible AI: Ethical Principles for Humanity</title><link href="https://www.benjaminpatch.com/posts/2024/Dec/11/responsible-ai-ethical-principles-for-humanity/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-11T10:07:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-11T10:07:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Benjamin Patch</name></author><id>tag:www.benjaminpatch.com,2024-12-11:/posts/2024/Dec/11/responsible-ai-ethical-principles-for-humanity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this brief but eye-opening exploration of responsible AI, you'll discover the critical ethical challenges facing our technological future. More than a cautionary tale, this article offers a roadmap for developing AI that amplifies human potential while safeguarding our fundamental values.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this brief but eye-opening exploration of responsible AI, you'll discover the critical ethical challenges facing our technological future. More than a cautionary tale, this article offers a roadmap for developing AI that amplifies human potential while safeguarding our fundamental values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you're a technologist, business leader, or simply someone curious about the profound impact of AI, you'll gain insights into how we can harness this revolutionary technology with wisdom, fairness, and foresight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Imperative of Responsible AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) accelerated by machine learning (ML) is transforming our world at breathtaking speed, promising breakthroughs in medicine, science, and industry. While I am inspired by the current and near-future potential of AI technology, I am also deeply concerned about the speed and direction we are traveling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The promise of artificial intelligence is staggering – imagine systems that can diagnose diseases earlier than human physicians, optimize complex global supply chains, or solve intricate scientific challenges that have long eluded human comprehension. Yet, this extraordinary potential comes with equally profound responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science fiction is filled with warnings of how unchecked technological development can lead to unintended consequences – and AI powered by machine learning is no longer confined to the safety of science fiction. Machine learning has become a powerful lens that can either amplify our collective human potential or exacerbate existing societal inequities. Responsible AI development is our critical checkpoint – ensuring that technological advancement serves humanity's broader interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real-World Stakes of Algorithmic Bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithmic bias of machine learning is not a theoretical problem – it’s a present-day reality with tangible human consequences. Here are a few real-world examples I found in my research:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon’s recruiting algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; (now scrapped) was proven to discriminate against female applicants (source: &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/world/insight-amazon-scraps-secret-ai-recruiting-tool-that-showed-bias-against-women-idUSKCN1MK0AG/"&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChatGPT-4&lt;/strong&gt; recommends fewer MRIs and stress tests for Black patients and female cardiology patients without sound medical reasoning (source: &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/sanfrancisco/news/ai-chatbots-are-supposed-to-improve-health-care-but-research-says-some-are-perpetuating-racism-2/"&gt;CBS News&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit scoring ML algorithms&lt;/strong&gt; routinely discriminate based on non-financial attributes like race and sex (source: &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00146-023-01676-3"&gt;Springer Nature&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Among dozens of other examples cited by &lt;a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/algorithmic-bias-detection-and-mitigation-best-practices-and-policies-to-reduce-consumer-harms/"&gt;The Brookings Institution&lt;/a&gt; and many other credible research groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence is clear and deeply troubling. Machine learning systems have already inadvertently perpetuated discriminatory practices across many aspects of modern society. Hence, our imperative need for more ethically responsible AI development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Workforce Disruption and Economic Recalibration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning will continue to fundamentally reshape our economic landscape. Not just by incremental changes but a potential restructuring of entire industries. Automation driven by AI could displace millions of jobs, particularly in sectors like manufacturing, transportation, customer service, and administrative work. Generative AI threatens creative fields such as writing, graphic design, video editing, and yes, even entry-level software developers – virtually all knowledge-based work could be at risk. Each worker can be empowered to do so much more, but fewer workers might be needed overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this isn't simply a narrative of job loss. We're also witnessing the emergence of entirely new job categories that didn't exist a few years ago, such as AI prompt engineering. Therefore, I strongly believe the key is &lt;strong&gt;proactive adaptation&lt;/strong&gt; – investing in reskilling programs, creating educational frameworks that prepare workers for an AI-integrated workforce, and developing policies that ensure economic transitions are equitable and supportive. If political leaders fail to deliver such adaptive programs and policies, it will likely lead to economic blowback not seen in generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Core Principles of Responsible AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect against the many potential harms of AI, &lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/blog/artificial-intelligence/responsible-ai"&gt;Atlassian&lt;/a&gt; and many other industry leaders advocate that four key principles must guide every project claiming to operate under the banner of ethically responsible AI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency:&lt;/strong&gt; AI must be explainable. Stakeholders should understand how decisions are made, and developers should document and share the inner workings of their systems. A lack of transparency can lead to mistrust and misuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fairness:&lt;/strong&gt; Bias in AI systems is one of the biggest ethical challenges. Developers need to carefully evaluate training datasets and outcomes to ensure algorithms don’t disproportionately harm or exclude certain groups. Regular audits can help identify and address potential issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy and Security:&lt;/strong&gt; As AI often relies on vast amounts of sensitive data, privacy and security should be top priorities. Encryption, anonymization, and secure coding practices are essential for safeguarding user information and preventing breaches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability:&lt;/strong&gt; Every AI decision should have a human touchpoint. When errors occur, there should be a clear chain of accountability to rectify problems quickly and learn from mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Considerations for Project Stakeholders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stakeholders have a unique responsibility to champion ethically responsible AI initiatives. Here’s how I suggest they contribute:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promote human oversight:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure there are checks and balances in place, especially for high-stakes decisions like loan approvals or medical diagnoses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assess societal impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Go beyond profit to consider how your AI solutions affect communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Champion diversity:&lt;/strong&gt; Building diverse teams helps mitigate bias and ensures your AI reflects a broader range of perspectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Best Practices for Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For software developers, responsible AI starts with adopting tools and frameworks designed to uphold ethical standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow ethical AI guidelines:&lt;/strong&gt; Frameworks from companies like &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/ai/responsible-ai"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://ai.google/responsibility/principles/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; can serve as roadmaps for creating trustworthy systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use bias detection tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Open-source resources like &lt;a href="https://aif360.res.ibm.com/"&gt;IBM’s AI Fairness 360&lt;/a&gt; toolkit can help developers identify and reduce bias in datasets and models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test and document rigorously:&lt;/strong&gt; Regular testing and thorough documentation are vital for ensuring transparency, fairness, and accountability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responsible AI in Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two quick examples of how ethically responsible AI development can be put into practice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Case Study 1: Reducing Bias in Hiring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tech company used an AI tool for candidate screening but discovered it favored male applicants due to historical bias in the data. By retraining the model on a more diverse dataset and introducing oversight checks, the company created a fairer hiring process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Case Study 2: Transparent Diagnostics in Healthcare&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A healthcare provider implemented an AI diagnostic tool with clear explanations for its decisions. Doctors could review the system’s recommendations, enhancing trust and enabling better patient care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Personal Call to Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my fellow technologists, policymakers, and innovators: we stand at a critical juncture. The AI and machine learning systems we develop today will shape human experiences for generations. Our choices matter – profoundly and irrevocably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsible AI is not about constraining innovation but channeling it toward meaningful, equitable outcomes. We must approach this technology with humility, foresight, and an unwavering commitment to human dignity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of artificial intelligence is not predetermined. It will be shaped by our collective choices, our ethical frameworks, and our willingness to prioritize human well-being over technological expediency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal commitment to ethically responsible AI development will remain a strong guiding principle as I develop real-world applications and training materials alike. I strongly encourage you to do the same and draw attention to oversights you might be exposed to. Our future can be extraordinarily bright so long as we develop AI responsibly today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your thoughts on responsible AI development? Feel free to reach me &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/benjaminpatch.bsky.social"&gt;@benjaminpatch on Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading and please code responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional references and sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/machine-learning/concept-responsible-ai?view=azureml-api-2"&gt;What is Responsible AI - Azure Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.iso.org/artificial-intelligence/responsible-ai-ethics"&gt;Building a responsible AI: How to manage the AI ethics debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/blog/artificial-intelligence/responsible-ai"&gt;Responsible AI: Key Principles and Best Practices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/think/topics/data-bias"&gt;What is Data Bias?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="AI Ethos"></category><category term="best practices"></category><category term="algorithmic bias"></category><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="generative ai"></category></entry></feed>